<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shubham&#39;s blog</title>
    <description>Some of my experiences with Music and Technology.
</description>
    <link>http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 11:58:24 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 11:58:24 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>HTML/CSS and other Web Design stuff for developers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s finally the day I took HTML/CSS or rather Web Designing more seriously. I’ve always been hesitant about writing HTML code from the time i was introduced to it in 8th Grade. Maybe because everything felt so static those days and all my friends were doing it. I decided to spend most of my time with system programming and mathematics, and Oh boy, i did really enjoy it! I’ve got around writing HTML code by using various templates and frameworks, but an urge to learn ‘HTML the hardway’ was building up inside of me. Now I have my Web Designing Exam tomorrow, and i think it’s now or never!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so here’s the starting HTML code provided by Atom text editor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;charset=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;utf-8&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 17:05:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/jekyll/update/2016/05/28/html-css-for-developers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/jekyll/update/2016/05/28/html-css-for-developers.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So..What&#39;s a Quantum Computer?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the fabrication of Intel 4004, the first ever microprocessor, CPUs have been getting smaller and more powerful. The microprocessors today are unbelievably faster and more versatile than computers a few decades ago. By fitting more and more transistors onto every microchip, engineers have continually halved the size and doubled the power of computers. Intel has also developed the popular, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/silicon-innovations/intel-tick-tock-model-general.html&quot;&gt;Tic-Tock model&lt;/a&gt;, “Tick” advances manufacturing technology, focusing on shrinking the chip, and “Tock” refers to architectural, thus capability advancements. If this trend continues, the size of the shrinking transistors would reach the size of atoms, the Quantum scale!
Such fabrications are challenged by various quantum effects&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 15:30:16 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/jekyll/update/2016/01/28/Blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/jekyll/update/2016/01/28/Blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A fresh new Start!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Heya!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Shubham Jain, I’m a third year Computer Science Engineering student at BVCOE, New Delhi. I am a programmer, Music Producer and an aspiring enterprenuer. As far music production is concerned, I am a vocalist (clean, screech, growls..), lyricist, guitarist and can play any standard stringed instrument by .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started blogging again for good! Having been recently introduced to the Open Source world,
I’m really enjoying contributing to some really exciting projects, but I think documenting my experience could be an even greater contribution for desperate coders like me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 13:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/jekyll/update/2016/01/22/start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://slayerjain.github.io/myblog/jekyll/update/2016/01/22/start.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
